ABIOYE OBALOLUWA PETER

Web: https://abioye-obaloluwa-peter.netlify.app/ Phone number: + 2348175885645 Email Address: abioyeobaloluwapeter@gmail.com GitHub: https://github.com/horbarz

Professional QA engineer with over 3 years of experience performing detailed agile testing of fintech, educational, ecommerce, and CRM-based software applications. Prodigious work experience in identifying, analyzing, and documenting software defects with extensive analytical skills, great manual and automation testing expertise, effective communication skills, solid attention to detail, and excellent ability to work in a team.

EXPERIENCE

QA Engineer – Appzone Group

May 2020 to Present

- Responsible for a group of 3 testers; assign tasks to the team, review test cases, and optimize if necessary.
- Manual execution of test cases based on the software requirement document.
- Extensively performed Regression, Exploratory, Load, Performance, API, and Smoke testing.
- Development of a traceability matrix to ensure all requirements are fulfilled.
- Defect tracking using Jira; Creating, prioritizing, and assigning bugs.
- Responsible for E2E test automation framework with 100+ Test cases for over 10 financial institutions.
- 50+ Test Cases running daily in CI/CD (Groovy, Selenium, Team city, and Git).
- Hands-on experience with various frameworks such as Data driven, Keyword Driven, Hybrid Approach, and Behavioral Driven Development (BDD).
- Developed reusable and generic methods that can be used across the automation framework which increased automation test script development by 70% and reduced automation cost and maintenance by 30%.
- Trained and mentored new employees on the company's testing strategies.
- Created test automation framework that handles card production, issuance, and personalization processes for over 10 financial institutions and reduced regression test time by 50%.
- Reduced app server consumption by 50% and cut necessary costs by 20% within a year.

Software Engineer - Sprinble

April 2019 – December 2019

- Built a teacher management web app using ASP.Net Core for the backend, AWS Services for media management, and React for the front end.
- Designed a simple domain-specific language to manage lesson contents for teachers.
- Design and implementation of UI test automation framework using Cypress and Jenkins.
- Regular interaction with the client to discuss functionality improvement.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science: Computer Engineering **Obafemi Awolowo University** - Ile-Ife, Osun State CGPA of 4.36/5.0 (**Top 5% of the program**)

May 2015 – December 2019

SKILLS

- Automation testing: Katalon, Cypress, Selenium
- Language: Javascript, C#, Java, Python
- Load testing: JMeter, LoadView
- Defect tracking and reporting: Jira

- **API testing**: Postman API
- CI/CD: Team City, and Jenkins
- Database Testing: SQL
- Test Framework: TestNG, NUnit, JUnit, Mocha

CERTIFICATION

- Selenium WebDriver with Java Issued by Test Automation University
- Advanced Cypress Issued by Test Automation University
- Test Automation in DevOps Issued by Test Automation University